Finding aid to the Stanley Curtis Ross papers. CA.MS.01145
Smith College Archives
Stanley Curtis Ross papers
1944-1967
Smith College Archives
Ross, Stanley Curtis
CA.MS.01145
0.854 linear feet (2 containers)
Contains papers related to Stanley Curtis Ross' time as an economics professor at Smith College, including correspondence, publications, news releases, photographs, programs to speeches, and retirement memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Biographical / Historical
Stanley Curtis Ross was a graduate of Otterbein College and the University of Chicago. He taught at Wayland Junior College for 25 years, during ten of which he was also president of the college. In 1943, Ross became a regional price economist in charge of Alaska, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands. In 1944, Ross came to Smith College to teach economics, where he gained a reputation for bridging the gap between the academic worlds and the world of business. Upon his retirement in 1961, Ross continued teaching at Smith, most commonly in a series of lectures on personal finance. He was ordained a minister, and filled many neighborhood pulpits, as well as taking the position of moderator for the First Congregational Church of Williamsburg. Ross died suddenly in 1967.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains papers related to Stanley Curtis Ross' professional life, including his correspondence with other academics and publishers, news articles and news releases about his life, photographs, programs to speeches he gave, and various pieces of Smith memorabilia from Ross' retirement.
Ross, Stanley Curtis; Ross, Stanley Curtis
- Biographical Information and Photographs, 1957-1966 (Box 992.1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1944-1964 (Box 992.1, Folder 2)
- News Articles and News Releases, 1944-1964 (Box 992.1, Folder 3)
- Speeches/Programs, 1945-1967 (Box 992.1, Folder 4)
- Post-War Cost of Living, no date (Box 992.1, Folder 5)
- Retirement Memorabilia, 1961 (Box 992.1, Folder 6)
- Translation: "Concerning the Ancient Peoples of Peru" from Apologetica Summaria de las Gentes Destas Indias (1555), 1948 (Box 992.1, Folder 7)
- Peru/Incans, lectures and research materials, 1958 (Box 992.1, Folder 8)
- Peru/Incans, letters, 1952 (Box 992.1, Folder 9)
- Peru/Incans, letters and correspondence, 1952 (Box 992.1, Folder 10)
- "Peru in 12 Minutes", no date (Box 992.1, Folder 11)
- Photographic slides, 1964; no date (Box 992.2)